# Jackie Barry

Intermediate/Secondary Science Teacher jacquelinebarry@nlesd.ca

709-697-9781

St. John's, Canada 💡

I am 26 years old and grew up in Ottawa before moving to St. John's to pursue my degree in Biochemistry (Nutrition) with a minor in Biology. I then completed a Masters of Science in Medicine in Immunology and Infectious Diseases with a focus in Virology. Following my MSc I completed my BEd (Int/Sec) and will be starting my Bachelor of Special Education in September (2019). I thrive in a team environment, and enjoy sharing my passion for science.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Junior High Teacher** Sheshatshiu Innu School

08/2018 - 07/2019

- Achievements/Tasks
- Develop teaching and learning materials for use in class, including lesson plans, homework, projects, assignments and exams.
- Modify lesson plans to suit students' current learning levels.
- Monitor and track student progress through various evaluation strategies.
- Work collaboratively with other teachers to provide individualized support for each student.
- Grade 7 (English and Health)
- Grade 8 Social Studies
- S.P.I.R.E Reading Intervention Program

# Internship

Holy Heart of Mary High School

01/2018 - 04/2018

St. John's, Newfoundland, Canada

NLESD

- Achievements/Tasks
- Promoted student engagement and motivation
- Designed and executed flexible lesson plans
- Evaluated student comprehension with suitable assessment strategies
- Science 1206
- Chemistry 2202
- Chemistry 3202
- IB Biology 3287

#### Tutor

St. John's, NL

01/2018 - 07/2018

- Achievements/Tasks
- Chemistry 2202 / Chemistry 3202
- Evaluate student comprehension and design targeted lesson plans
- Create resources to supplement classroom learning

## **SKILLS**

Kurzweil 3000 Aladin Rainbow Pro

WordQ SpeakQ

Graphic Organizers

Microscope

Powerschool

Schoology

Microsoft Office

G Suite

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Special Education Memorial University of Newfoundland

09/2019 - P

Bachelor of Education (Intermediate and Secondary)

Memorial University of Newfoundland 09/2017 – 08/2018

Master of Science in Medicine
Memorial University of Newfoundland

09/2015 - 10/2017

- Thesis
- A novel method for viral protein tracking in host cells
- Received a CanHepC Fellowship valued at \$20,000/year

**Bachelor of Science** 

Memorial University of Newfoundland

09/2011 - 04/2015

3.0

- Course
- Biochemistry (Nutrition) Major
- Biology Minor

#### CERTIFICATES

American Sign Language Level 101 (04/2018 – 07/2018)

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Teaching Fellow**

# Oceans Learning Partnership

09/2017 - 12/2017

- Achievements/Tasks
- Designed curriculum based resources for the Biology 2201 Ocean Science Centre Visit
- Facilitated school visits to the Ocean Science Centre
- Integrated technology into the structured activities

# Immunology Teaching Assistant Memorial University of Newfoundland

01/2017 - 04/2017

- Achievements/Tasks
- Taught lectures pertaining to my research interests
- Graded midterm and final exams

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# **Beaver Leader**

Scouts Canada

11/2015 - P

1st MacPherson Scouts

Tasks/Achievements

Received Certificate of Commendation (2016, 2017)

Contact: Neva Fudge – nevafudge@gmail.com

# Senior Mentors MUN Mentors

01/2014 - 09/2017

Memorial University of Newfoundland

Tasks/Achievements

Received Certificate of Distinction (2014, 2015, 2016)

Contact: Julia Hiscock - Julia.hiscock@dal.ca

# **LANGUAGES**



### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

#### Certified ABA Home Therapist (03/2019)

 Completion of the ABA home therapy program designed to support individuals with Autism Spectrum Disorder.

# Fountas & Pinnell Benchmark Assessment Systems (09/2018 – 07/2019)

 Determining students baseline reading levels based on their reading behaviours, comprehension and fluency.

# S.P.I.R.E (Specialized Program Individualizing Reading Excellence) (09/2018 – 07/2019)

 Implementation of small group reading intervention designed to increase literacy.

# Provincial Learning Disabilities Conference (04/2018)

 Learning Disabilities Association of Newfoundland and Labrador

# Safe Schools & Emergency Procedures (11/2017)

- Michelle Clemens, MUN

### Mediasmarts: Digital Literacy (10/2017)

Matthew Johnson, MUN

#### **INTERESTS**



## **REFERENCES**

#### Greg Quilty - Principal

Contact: gquilty@innueducation.ca - 709-899-4866

#### Lori Hudson - Vice-Principal

Contact: lhudson@innueducation.ca - 709-899-3142

#### Miranda Coldwell - ABA Therapy Employer

Contact: 709-987-2448

# Aimee Hann - Teacher

Contact: aimeehann@nlesd.ca - 709-764-8946